Before we get started we need to purchase our fabric.
And there's a few things to consider while you're buying your fabric.
The width of the fabric can come in different sizes.
The standard for upholstery fabric is usually 60 inches wide.
But you can find fabrics that are 45 inches wide or 70 depending upon the fabrics.
You want to make sure that you take into account what width fabric you're buying to figure out how much you're going to need when you're estimating how much you're going to need for your couch.
Now you also want to take into account the pattern.
Now if you're using something where you're going to want to match patterns you'll need more fabric.
You'll need a lot of extra if you're matching.
You also want to think about how it's going to lay on the couch, whether it's horizontal or vertical.
And that will also have an effect on how much fabric you'll be using.